(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T10:15:12.245143",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ブラック★ロックシューター どこへ行ったの?
Black★Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか?
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much longer do I have to shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much longer do I have to cry?
もうやめて わたしはもう走れない
Stop already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing.
真っ暗で明かりもない
In this pitch dark, lightless,
崩れかけたこの道で
and crumbling path...
あの時の希望が見えた気がした どうして
I felt like I saw hope from back then... Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶
Black★Rock Shooter, nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
of those days when we just had fun.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black★Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇をかける星に願いを
Make a wish upon the star running through the dark.
もう一度だけ走るから
I'll run just one more time.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
Murmuring with a trembling, frightened voice,
わたしの名前を呼んで
please call out my name.
何処へ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいのだろう
How much more should I shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいのだろう
How much more should I cry?
もうやめて
Stop it already,
わたしはもう走れない
I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of closes up.
真っ暗で明かりもない
Pitch-black and unlit,
崩れかけたこの道で
on this crumbling road
あるはずもないあの時の希望が見えた気がした
I felt like I saw hope that shouldn't exist.
どうして？
Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター 懐かしい記憶
Black Rock Shooter, nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
simply of those fun times.
ブラック★ロックシューター でも動けないよ
Black Rock Shooter, but I can't move.
闇を駈ける星に願いを
I wish upon the stars shooting through the darkness,
もう一度だけ走るから
because I'll run just once more.
怖くて震える声でつぶやく わたしの名前を呼んで
Whispering with a trembling voice, "Call my name."
夜明けを抱く空 境界線までの距離 あと一歩届かない
Dawn-embracing sky, distance to the boundary, not reaching by one step.
こらえた涙があふれそうなの 今下を向かないで
Tears I held back are about to overflow; don't look down now.
止まってしまう
Stopping in my tracks.
未来を生きていたいんだ わかったの 思い出して
I want to live in the future; I understand, remember.
強く強く信じるの
Firmly, firmly believing.
そうよ
That's right.
ブラック★ロックシューター 優しい匂い
Black Rock Shooter, tender scent.
痛いよ 辛いよ 飲み込む言葉
"It hurts, it's tough," swallowing those words.
ブラック★ロックシューター 動いてこの足！
Black Rock Shooter, move these feet!
世界を超えて 最初からわかっていた ここにいることを
Overcoming the world! Since the beginning, I've known I'm here.
わたしのなかの 全ての勇気が 火をともして もう逃げないよ
All the courage inside of me lights the fire, and I won't flee anymore!
ブラック★ロックシューター ひとりじゃないよ 声を上げて泣いたって構わない
Black Rock Shooter, you're not alone! I don't mind if you cry out loud.
ブラック★ロックシューター 見ていてくれる 今から始まるの わたしの物語
Black Rock Shooter, you'll be watching me. My story starts now.
忘れそうになったら この歌を 歌うの
When you seem to be forgetting it, I'll sing this song!
えー、こんばんは！
Um, good evening!
ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！
I'm Tokoyami Towa of Hololive 4th Gen!
やっほー！いぇーい！
Yahoo! Yay!
はい、始りました！
Yes, it has started!
常闇トワ生誕祭2024、レッツゴー！
Tokoyami Towa's Birthday Festival 2024, let's go!
えー、ハッシュタグ「常闇トワ生誕祭2024」でたくさん呟いてください！
Um, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #TokoyamiTowaBirthday2024!
ポストしてね！
Make posts, okay?
よろしく目指せトレンド入り！
Let's aim for trending!
ゴー！
Go!
ということで、最初の1曲目「ブラック★ロックシューター」いかがでしたでしょうか？
So, how did you like the first song, "Black Rock Shooter"?
演出がすごいかっこよかったでしょ？
The production was super cool, right?
スタジオのみんなが頑張ってくれました、運営さんね、頑張っていただきました！いぇーい！
Everyone at the studio worked hard, management worked hard! Yay!
その、VJっていうかモニターがね、すごいかっこいいの、ほら見て！
And the VJ, or rather the monitors, are super cool, look!
このモニターが4分割になってくっついて！
These monitors split into four and connected!
ということで、結構ねこのモニターに仕掛けが今回はあるので、この後のね曲、あのいっぱい歌うんですけれども、どういう風な仕掛けがあるのかとかも楽しみながら見ていただけ……くれたらと思います！いぇーい！
So, since there are quite a few gimmicks on this monitor this time, as for the songs after this, well, I'll be singing a lot, but I hope you'll enjoy seeing what kind of gimmicks there are! Yay!
そして、今回のライブテーマはカラフルになっておりまして、
And the theme of this live is colorful,
1曲目がブラック★ロックシューター！
and the first song was Black Rock Shooter!
ということで、えーじゃあこの後の曲、どんな曲名の、どんな曲が、どんな曲が、どんな曲名が来るのかなんちゅうてな！
So, um, I wonder what kind of song title, what kind of song will come next, you know!
はい、ということでゲストもたくさん来るのでお楽しみに！
Yes, so guests will be coming a lot too, so look forward to it!
はい、では皆さん楽しんでいってください！早速次の曲いってみきたいと思います！レッツゴー！
Yes, everyone, please enjoy! I'd like to try going to the next song right away! Let's go!
つまりは好奇心に囚われてたんだ
In other words, I was trapped in curiosity,
大切なものなら壊したんだ
breaking everything precious.
明かりの灯らないホールケーキ
A whole cake with no light,
木製の君と踊ってたんだ
I was dancing with your wooden self.
クローゼットで待った今日も小さな身体寄せ合って
Waiting in the closet today too, huddling our small bodies,
眠るのさ 変わるのさ 想像 容易 安全
we'll sleep, we'll change, imagination, easy, safe.
私 馬鹿な子なの どこにも行かないで
I'm a foolish child, don't go anywhere.
濁った正体の鉤目を覚ませ
Awaken the latch of the clouded true form,
夜のうち片付けたおもちゃ 無邪気なままでまだいたかった
the toys packed away overnight, wanting to stay innocent still.
愛情はhigh ただ捨てるばかり 剥がれ落ちた大事な記憶
Affection is high, just throwing it away, peeling away precious memories.
But 後悔 low-life ならば敢えて ありえないことを願う夏を
But if regret is low-life, I'll dare to wish for an impossible summer,
YELLOW
あいつは好奇心に殺されたようだ
He seemed to have been killed by curiosity,
狡猾な術なら試したんだ
trying out sly methods.
うだつの上がらないあんな行為
Such lackluster behavior,
満面の笑みで歌ってたんだ
singing with a blank smile.
クローゼットで待った今日は一人で待つならこんなもんか
Waiting in the closet today alone, is this all there is to waiting?
変わるのさ 終わりのさ 肯定
It'll change, it'll end, confirmation,
求め続ける 価値 価値 価値
continuing to seek worth, worth, worth.
迫る秒針 もっと捲いて
As the second hand approaches, roll it up more,
業深くなって 終いには 天地が 逆さまになる
growing deep in karma until heaven and earth go upside down.
なんで どうして ほら 霞んだ透明
Why? How come? See, it's blurred and transparent.
窓から見た景色を まだ覚えています
"I still remember the scenery I saw out the window."
いっそ消えて無くなるだけの YELLOW
The YELLOW that's better off just disappearing.
あいつは好奇心に殺されたようだ
He seemed to have been killed by curiosity,
狡猾な術なら試したんだ
trying out sly methods.
二度とあがらないあんな恋を
Such unrising love,
満面な笑みで歌ってたんだ
singing with a full smile.
クローゼットで待った今日は一人で待つならこんなもんか
Waiting in the closet today alone, is this all there is to waiting?
変わるのさ 終わりのさ 肯定 求め続ける 価値 価値 価値
It'll change, it'll end, confirmation, seeking worth, worth, worth.
迫る秒針 もっと捲いて 業深くなって
As the second hand approaches, roll it up deeper,
終いには 天地が 逆さまになる
until heaven and earth go upside down.
なんで どうして ほら 霞んだ透明 窓から見た景色を まだ覚えてます
Why? How come? See, blurred transparent scenery from the window, I still remember.
ひっそり消えて無くなるだけの YELLOW
The YELLOW that quietly disappears.
その日が来ないよう わざわざ間違えて
Purposely making mistakes so that day won't arrive,
崩壊した 乖離と解脱
collapsed divergence and release.
救いなどないよう 限界あるなんて まだ想う熱
With no salvation, still feeling the heat of having limits.
愛情はhigh ただ捨てるばかり 剥がれ落ちた大事な記憶
Affection is high, just throwing it away, peeling away precious memories.
But 後悔 low-life ならば敢えて
But if regret is low-life, I'll dare
ありえないことを願う夏を
to wish for an impossible summer.
その日が来ないよう わざわざ間違えて
Purposely making mistakes so that day won't arrive,
崩壊した 乖離と解脱
collapsed divergence and release.
救いなどないよう 限界あるなんて まだ想う熱
With no salvation, still feeling the heat of having limits.
愛情はhigh ただ捨てるばかり 剥がれ落ちた大事な記憶
Affection is high, just throwing it away, peeling away precious memories.
But 後悔 low-life ならば敢えて ありえないことを願う夏を
But if regret is low-life, I'll dare to wish for an impossible summer.
さよなら。は言わない 約束もない
We won't say goodbye, we don't need promises.
また 会える から 僕ら は
Because we'll meet again, that's us.
オレンジ を 少し かじる 地平線
Taking a bite of the orange horizon,
甘酸っぱい 光 眩しく て
the bittersweet light is dazzling.
すべり出す 汗 と 響いた 声
The sweat trickling down and voices echoing,
叩き合え た 肩 笑いあって 泣いて
our shoulders touching as we laugh and cry together.
明日へ 向かう オレンジ色 の 空 へ 羽ばたいていく
Heading towards tomorrow, into the orange-colored sky we spread our wings.
あと 1秒 だけ もう 1秒 だけ
Just one more second, just one more second,
なんて 惜しむ よう な 今 が きっと
as if cherishing this moment right now, surely.
小さな 背中 に 大きな 夢 を 乗せて
Carrying big dreams on our small backs,
ここ まで 来 た ん だ よ
we've come this far.
思い通り の 未来 だけ じゃ ない けど
It's not just the future we envisioned,
楽しかった よね 全部 が
but it was all enjoyable.
息 を 切らし ただ 走り 続け
Out of breath, we just kept running,
追いかけ て た の は 胸 の 熱さ だろ
what we were chasing was the warmth in our hearts.
もう 一 回 のない そんな 瞬間 が
There won't be another chance, in those moments,
ずっ と 繋がっ て いく よう に
may they always be connected.
何 を 描こう か ? 何 を しよう か ?
What should we envision? What should we do?
なんて 想像 し て みる けど きっと
We try to imagine, but surely...
小さな肩を並べて歩いた
We walked with our small shoulders side by side,
何でもないことで笑い合っていた
laughing together over nothing in particular.
同じ夢を見つめていた
We were looking at the same dream.
耳を澄ませば
If I clear my ears,
今でも聴こえる 君の声
I can still hear your voice.
オレンジ色に染まる街の中
The town is stained in an orange color.
君がいないと本当に退屈だね
It's truly boring when you're not around.
寂しいと言えば笑われてしまうけれど
If I say I'm lonely, people will just laugh at me,
残されたもの 何度も確かめるよ
but I'll check the things left behind again and again,
消えることなく輝いている
shining brightly without fading away.
雨上がりの空のような
Like the sky after the rain,
心が晴れるような
like a heart clearing up,
君の笑顔を憶えている
I remember your smile.
思い出して笑顔になる
Remembering it makes me smile.
きっと二人はあの日のまま
Surely, the two of us will remain just as we were that day,
無邪気な子供のまま
like innocent children,
巡る季節を駆け抜けていく
running through the revolving seasons,
それぞれの明日を見て
looking toward our respective tomorrows.
一人になれば不安になると眠りたい夜は話し続けていた
Whenever I'm alone and feel anxious, on nights when I didn't want to sleep,
話し続けていた
we just kept talking.
君はこれから何を見ていくんだろう
What will you be looking at from now on?
私はここで何を見ていくのだろう
What will I be looking at right here?
沈む夕焼け
In the setting sunset,
オレンジに染まる街に
in the town stained orange,
そっと涙を預けてみるの
I'll gently entrust my tears.
何億もの光の中生まれた一つの愛
One love born among millions of lights,
変われなくても変わってしまっても
no matter if it changes or stays the same,
君は君だよ 心配ないよ
you are you, so don't worry.
いつか二人大人になって
Someday, when we grow up,
素敵な人に出会って
meet wonderful people,
かけがえのない家族を連れて
and bring irreplaceable families,
この場所で逢えるといいな
it would be nice to meet here again.
見つめられたら それだけで甘い 花 が 香り だす
Just with a single gaze, a sweet flower begins to fragrance.
誰 に も 話し ちゃ いけない よ
You mustn't tell anyone.
夢なら 覚めないで 桃源郷
If it's a dream, please don't wake me up, Peach Blossom Land.
一つ 噛みれば 密 の 味やめ ないで 戻れ なく て も
With one bite, the taste of nectar. Don't stop, even if we can't go back.
ヒラヒラリ 舞って 落ち ゆく染め られて 望み の まま に
Dancing and falling, fluttering away, drowning in it just as desired.
口づけ くらい じゃ 足りない ウォーアイニー夜 が 終わる まで 踊り ましょう
A single kiss isn't enough, wo ai ni. Let's dance until the night ends.
指 と 指 を 絡ませて桃 の 雫 飲み干せば
Entwining our fingers together, if we drink down the peach's drops,
この まま 離れ たく ないどうか 消え ないで 桃源郷
I don't want to be separated like this. Please don't disappear, Peach Blossom Land.
もう一つ 噛みれば 罪 の 味怖く ない あなた と なら ば
With another bite, the taste of sin. I'm not scared if I'm with you.
ハラハラリ 咲いて 散り ゆく揺ラサレテ この 恋ゴコロ
Blooming and scattering, fluttering away, this romantic heart is shaken.
欲しい のは 一つ あなた の ウォーアイニーこの 身 果てる まで 謳い ましょう
The only thing I want is you, wo ai ni. Let's sing until this body gives out.
ヒラヒラリ 舞って 落ち ゆく染め られて 望み の まま に
Dancing and falling, fluttering away, drowning in it just as desired.
口づけ くらい じゃ 足りない ウォーアイニー夜 が 終わる まで 踊り ましょう
A single kiss isn't enough, wo ai ni. Let's dance until the night ends.
ハラハラリ 咲いて 散り ゆく揺ラサレテ この 恋ゴコロ
Blooming and scattering, fluttering away, this romantic heart is shaken.
欲しい のは 一つ あなた の ウォーアイニーこの 身 果てる まで 謳い ましょう
The only thing I want is you, wo ai ni. Let's sing until this body gives out.
見つめられたら それだけで
With just a gaze,
甘い花が 香りだす
sweet flowers begin to bloom with fragrance.
「誰にも話しちゃいけないよ」
“You mustn't tell anyone.”
夢なら覚めないで 桃源郷
If it's a dream, don't wake me up, Utopia.
一つ噛みれば 密の味
With one bite, the taste of nectar.
やめないで 戻れなくても
Don't stop, even if we can't turn back.
ヒラヒラリ 舞い落ちてゆく
Fluttering and falling down,
染められて 望みのままに
dyed just as desired.
口づけくらいじゃ 足りない ウォー・アイ・ニーズ
A mere kiss isn't enough, wo ai ni—
夜が終わるまで 踊りましょう
Let's dance until the night ends.
才能なんてないから ここで一生泣いているんだろ
I've got no talent to call my own, so I must be crying here for life.
目に映った景色の中の青さが 羨しく思っていた
I envied the blueness of the scenery reflected in my eyes.
路肩に転がる人生 アスファルトの温度下がっている
A life rolling by the roadside, the asphalt's temperature is dropping.
真夜中を照らす灯りを求め つなぐ電波セカイへと
Seeking a light to illuminate the midnight, connecting to a radio wave world.
求めるものだけ描いた
I drew only what I desired.
心閉まって待って!
Holding back my heart, wait!
本当は叫びたいのよ
Honestly, I want to scream.
強くありたいと願った
I wished to be strong.
声は無情に散らして 孤独を奏る
My voice scatters callously, playing solitude.
指先から伝わってく 虚しの色
Flowing from my fingertips, a colorless sense of emptiness.
認めてはくれないの? 燻んでしまったの灰色に
“Won't you acknowledge me?” Smoldered into a dull gray.
こんな才能なんて借り物 まだ人生終わっていないから
Such talent is just borrowed, my life isn't over yet.
諦めんなって誰かの声 見失ってしまったのアイロニー
“Don't give up,” someone's voice. I lost sight of the irony.
気付かなくて今も抗ってる この感情奪っていってよ
Unaware, I'm still fighting back. Steal away these feelings
ドロドロになってしまう前に
before they turn into a muddy mess.
私だけみて愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんなセカイとバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye-bye to this world.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting my bleeding thoughts.
夢の形に泣いちゃっていた
Crying into the shape of a dream.
いつかはできると思っていた だけど現実人は残酷だな
I thought I'd be able to someday, but reality is cruel.
焦りと不安の謎の間に 黒くなって浮かんでいる
Floating in black between impatience and anxiety.
退屈なセンスと 曖昧な表現なんかじゃ
With boring sense and vague expressions,
奇を衒った奴らの芸術に 飲み込まれて消えていく
getting swallowed up by the art of those who seek attention.
雨と流れていく徒労感
A sense of futility flowing with the rain.
肩を濡らして残った 冷たい記憶の体温
The body temperature of cold memories remaining on my wet shoulders.
雲の隙間から覗いた 光当たって届いて
Light peering through the clouds reaches down,
身体を軽くしたんだよ
making my body feel light.
美学とかプライドとか語る前に やれることやっていけ
Before talking about aesthetics or pride, “Just do what you can do.”
閉ざしてしまったの退路に 焼いた才能を一つ置いていけ
Leave behind a burned talent on the retreat route you closed off.
ただやったもん勝ちなんじゃない? 固唾飲んでる場合じゃないでしょ!
Isn't it just whoever does it wins? This is no time to hold your breath!
目を開いても変わらぬアイロニー 気付いていたってどうしようもないから
An unchanging irony even when opening my eyes, but since there's nothing I can do,
それを虎視眈々と狙っている ペルソナになんて越されないよ
I'm eyeing it hawk-eyed; I won't let a persona surpass me.
私だけみて愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんなセカイとバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye-bye to this world.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting my bleeding thoughts.
言の葉の意味飲み込んで
Swallowing the meaning of words.
燻んでしまったの灰色に 借り物の才能なんていらない
Smoldered into a dull gray, I don't need borrowed talent.
まだ人生終わっていないから 諦めんなって誰かの声
My life isn't over yet, someone's voice saying “Don't give up.”
見失ってしまったのアイロニー 気付かなくて今も抗ってる
I lost sight of the irony, unaware and still fighting back.
この感情奪っていってよ ドロドロになってしまう前に
Steal away these feelings before they turn into a muddy mess.
私だけみて愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんなセカイとバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye-bye to this world.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting my bleeding thoughts.
夢の形に笑っていた
Smiling into the shape of a dream.
燻んでしまったの灰色に 焼けた才能を一つ置いていけ
Smoldered into a dull gray, leave behind a burned talent.
ただやったもん勝ちなんじゃない? 固唾飲んでる場合じゃないでしょ!
Isn't it just whoever does it wins? This is no time to hold your breath!
目を開いても変わらぬアイロニー 気付いていたってどうしようもないから
An unchanging irony even when opening my eyes, but since there's nothing I can do,
それを越したんだって戸惑ってる ビル群なんて壊されんよ
I'm bewildered that I surpassed it; skyscraper clusters won't be destroyed.
私だけみて愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんなセカイとバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye-bye to this world.
滲む想いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting my bleeding thoughts.
言の葉の意味飲み込んで
Swallowing the meaning of words.
こんなセカイとバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye-bye to this world.
才能なんてないからここで一生泣いているんだろ
I've got no talent, so I'm crying here for the rest of my life...
目に映った景色の一色が羨しく思っていた
The blue of the scenery reflecting in my eyes felt so enviable
路肩に転がる人生アスファルトの温度下がっている
A life tumbled by the roadside, asphalt losing its warmth
真夜中を照らす灯りを求め迷う電波セカイへと
Seeking a light to illuminate midnight, wandering into a radio-wave world
Rainy Rainy 求めるものだけ描いた
Rainy Rainy, I only drew what I desired
心閉まって待って！本当は叫びたいのよ
Locking my heart away, wait! Honestly, I just want to scream
Rainy Rainy 強くありたいと願った
Rainy Rainy, I wished to be strong
声は無情に散って 孤独を奏でる
My voice scatters calllessly, playing a lonely melody
指先から伝わってく虚しさの色彩
The color of emptiness passing through my fingertips
“認めてはくれないの？”
"Won't you acknowledge me?"
燻んでしまったの灰色に
Fading into a dull shade of gray
こんな才能なんて借り物 まだ人生終わっていないから
Borrowed talent like this... My life isn't over yet
諦めんなって誰かの声
"Don't give up," someone's voice says
見失ってしまったのアイロニー
Lost sight of myself, oh the irony
気付けなくて今も抗っている
Unaware, I'm still fighting back
この感情奪って去ってよ
Take these feelings away and leave
ドロドロになってしまう前に
Before everything turns into a messy sludge
wow..私だけみて愛を伝えて
wow... look only at me and pass on the love
wow..こんなセカイとバイバイバイバイ
wow... saying bye-bye-bye-bye to this world
wow..滲む想いなぞって描いた
wow... tracing and drawing blurring thoughts
wow..夢の形に泣いちゃった
wow... crying into the shape of a dream
白い雪のプリンセスは
[Title: Shiroi Yuki no Princess wa]
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん 世界で一番可愛がるのはやめてよ
Mirror, mirror, on the wall, stop calling me the fairest of them all!
棘のような視線迫る 優しいふりした彼女が
Glares like thorns close in, as she puts on a kind face
素敵な晩餐もてなされた そっと口に含んで
Serving a wonderful dinner, as I take a tentative bite
薄れていく意思の中で夢を見る いつかの童話
Having dreams in fading consciousness, like a fairy tale
時間が止まる お願い kissで目を覚まして欲しいの
Time stops. Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように 突き刺す憎しみはドラマチックな事情
Like taking me out of a white casket, piercing hatred is a dramatic affair
祈っても 王子様ーきみーはまだ来ない
Even if I pray, my prince—you—still haven't come
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん ネクタイ任せや頬に挨拶するから
Mirror, mirror, mr. mirror, fixing ties and greeting cheeks
姫みを買わされてしまった 7人の小人いるけど
Bought into being the princess, though there are seven dwarfs
助ける素振り、知らんふりネ… そっと首を掴まれ
Acting like they'll help, playing dumb... gently grabbing my neck
一粒の涙さえも拭えなくて 呼吸もままならない
Unable to even wipe away a single tear, struggling to breathe
視界失った 消えそうだから早くかけて欲しいの
Losing my vision, I'm about to vanish so hurry and come
訳は聞けないで応えられない 望まない憎まれは深い愛の二乗
Can't ask why, can't answer, unwanted hatred is the square of deep love
もうすぐでいなくなってしまうのかな 途切れてく命の音
Will I be gone soon? The sound of fading life
毒リンゴを食した少女のように 眠りにつく
Like a girl who ate a poisoned apple, falling asleep
お願い kissで目を覚まして欲しいの 胸の中の声届きますか
Please, wake me up with a kiss. Does the voice in my heart reach you?
階段を上ったらドアを開けるだけで 見つかるよ
Climbing the stairs, just opening the door, and I'll be found
お願い kissで目を覚まして欲しいの 白い棺から連れ出すように
Please, wake me up with a kiss, like taking me out of a white casket
突き刺す憎しみはドラマチックな事情 祈っても 王子様ーきみーはまだ来ない
Piercing hatred is a dramatic affair. Even if I pray, my prince—you—still haven't come
消えてしまうその前に…
Before I fade away...
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん 猫背気味な背中見合わせ
Mirror, mirror, mr. mirror, catching each other's slouched backs
アブダクションするから 瞳を奪われてしまった
Being abducted, having our eyes stolen away
7つのゴビとはいるけど 助ける素振り知らんふりネ… そっと首を掴まれ
There are seven goblins, but pretending not to notice... gently grabbing my neck
ひと粒の涙さえも 涙さえも…
Even a single tear, even a single tear...
呑み込めなくて 呼吸もままならないし 返してくれた
Unable to swallow, struggling to breathe, you gave it back
消えそうだから 早くかけて欲しいの 訳は聞かないで
I'm about to vanish, so please hurry and come, don't ask why
答えられない 望まない憎まれは 深い愛の事情 もうすぐで
Can't answer, unwanted hatred is the depth of love, soon...
いなくなるのかな…
Will I be gone...
途切れてく 命の音
The fading sound of life...
独り人形のように 眠りにつく
Falling asleep like a lonely doll...
鏡よ 鏡 よ 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
世界で一番可愛いのは
who is the fairest of them all?
胸の中の声 届きますか
Can you hear the voice inside my heart?
階段を上ったら ドアを開けるだけで 見つかるよ
Climb the stairs, just open the door, and you'll find it.
鏡よ 鏡 よ 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
白い棺が 連れ去るように
as if the white coffin carries me away,
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマティックな事情
the piercing hatred is a dramatic affair.
祈っても君はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, you still haven't come.
消えてしまう
Disappearing...
お願い キスで目覚めさせ欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
胸の中の歌と届きますか
can you hear the song inside my heart?
階段を上ったら ドアを開けるだけで 見つかるよ
Climb the stairs, just open the door, and you'll find it.
はあ… よかった！
Haah... That's a relief!
ということで、オルースから橘ひなのちゃんが来てくれました！
So, Tachibana Hinano-chan has come over from VEE!
こんにちは！こんばんは！か？
Hello! Good evening, I guess?
こんばんは！
Good evening!
VEE所属の橘ひなのなので…！イエーイ！
As Hinano Tachibana from VEE... Yay!
どうだった？ マジで疲れた！
How was it? - I'm seriously exhausted!
いやでも、本当にね、一緒に踊れてよかった！初めてだもんね、3Dでコラボするの。
It's our first time collaborating in 3D.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
結構前に、実家その3Dになったらコラボしようねって、まだその時は3Dになってなくて。
We talked about collaborating once we both got 3D models.
え、そうだっけ？
Eh, is that right?
そうだよ！
That's right!
そうだよ、ゲームしてる時にさ、してたそんな話。
We were talking about that while playing games.
そう、だから、そう3Dになったりするからコラボしようねっていう話をしてて、念願を、ついにね、呼んでいただけました。
Our wish finally came true—you invited me!
緊張してない？ ありがとう、ちょっと緊張してます。しかも、疲れすぎだろ！
Thanks, I'm a bit nervous. And man, I'm way too tired!
これね、やっぱトワ様はアイドルですけど。
Well, Towa-sama is an idol, after all.
私、私、一般ゲーマーなんで、ちょっとその体力の方がね。
But I'm just an ordinary gamer, so my physical stamina...
なんか自分の記念日とかに踊ったりしててさ、ちょこちょこ。
You know, I'd sometimes dance for my own anniversary streams.
まあまあまあ、でも、そんな、ちょっと…おばあ、やめてよ！
Well, still, such a... Granny, stop it!
おばあやめてよ、だから！しょうがないじゃん。
Stop calling me a granny! It can't be helped.
今日、トワ様は誕生日なんだけど…
Today is Towa-sama's birthday, but...
たーちゃん！たーちゃんおめでとう！やったー！
Happy birthday to Hina-chan! Yay!
星がり！星がりなのよ、星がりなのよ、いつもの、いつものやつね！
Seeking attention as always! The usual routine!
え、ちなみにこれダンスレッスンよね、一緒にやって面白かったことがあったんだよね。そう。ちょっと言ってくださいよ。
We did dance lessons together, and something funny happened. Tell them about it.
あの、サビに、サビに入る前に、私たちこうやって、こうやってやってたじゃないですか。こうやって重なって。
Before entering the chorus, we did this pose where we overlap like this, right?
そう、私、あんとき前だっけ？
Yeah, was I in front back then?
1サビが、1サビ前が、トワが前で、こう、こういう感じなんだよね。
For the first chorus, Towa was in front, making this kind of pose.
で、2サビが反対なんだよね。そう、私、本当はこうなんだよね。
And for the second chorus, it's reversed. I'm actually supposed to be like this.
そう、練習するんだけど、なんか、自分の顔と、同じ顔なの。
We practiced using the mirror, but because of the same pose...
これ、トワがこうやって顔が見えるんですよ。自分の顔がこうやってやった時に、でも目の前にひなのが同じポーズでこうやってやってるから、「え？見えない！」って、まったく見えなくて。
I couldn't see anything at all because Hina was right in front of me.
それでおね、しばらくツボってたんだよね。しばらく、めっちゃだいぶツボってた。
And because of that, we cracked up for a while.
だいぶツボって、そのあと、普通に合ってるのにこれが、ちゃん合ってるのに、なんか…そう、そう、そう…引っぱってたんだけど、今日はできてよかったでーす！
We laughed so much, but I'm glad we pulled it off today!
ということではい、今日は8月8日なんですけれども。
And so, today is August 8th.
なんか今月末にもね、はい、なんかVSAっていうのがありまして、今日は仲良く踊って歌ったんですけども、ライブになります！
At the end of this month, there's an event called VSA, and we'll have a live performance!
お互いね、リーダー枠、いつもね。そう。
We're both in the leader spots, as usual.
いやー、去年、去年もね、私もあなたもちょっと苦しいよやめよう。で、今年も、お互いね、ライブあるけど、払拭しよう、去年のライブは頑張りましょう。
Let's shake off last year's and do our best at the live.
頑張るということで、VSAもよろしくお願いします！お願いします！
We'll do our best, so please look forward to VSA too!
はい、というわけで、じゃあ次の曲へどうぞって一緒に言ってもらえますか？
Could you join me in saying "Now, on to the next song"?
もちろん！じゃあなんか、お互いに好きなポーズしよう。わかった。これね、結構大事だから、これ仲良しの大事だから。
Of course! Let's strike our favorite poses together.
え、じゃあ次の曲へどうぞ行こう。せーの、次の曲へどうぞー！
Then let's move on to the next song. Ready, set, on to the next song!
残された 呼吸を 使い果たせば
If I use up the remaining breath,
抱き止めた 記憶さえ 肺へと散る 孤独と
even the memories I held onto scatter into my lungs as loneliness—
気づきながら
while realizing it,
惨烈者は 笑い行く 移ろいなき棺
the ruthless one walks away to an unchanging coffin.
その叫びもやがて過去に溶ける
That cry will soon dissolve into the past,
乱反射のあなたをも道づれに
taking you of diffuse reflection along as well.
いやだよ 終わるために生まれた悲劇など
I hate it—tragedies born just to end.
息を止めて そのままで 命を銀に浸かれ
Holding your breath, staying just like that, bathing your life in silver,
果てなき夢がいつまでも続きますように
may this endless dream continue forever—
消えたくないよ 消えたいで、ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to disappear, I want to disappear—I prayed for just that alone.
最後の 最後の 幸せ
our final, final happiness,
誰にも 誰にも 奪わせない
I won't let anyone, anyone take it away.
離さない
I won't let go.
散り慣れた 世界は 狂いだろうか
Is the world used to scattering going mad?
目を背け 死神に怯える あなたのは
Turning away and trembling before the reaper, yours is...
濡れる日の 鮮やかさを 持って早歩こう
Walking fast with the vividness of rainy days,
白日は 泣き続ける その結末を思い出せ
daylight keeps weeping, remembering that ending.
答えも届かずに朽ちてゆく其の日が
That day will rot away without even reaching an answer.
息を止めて そのままで 命を銀に浸かれ
Holding your breath, staying just like that, bathing your life in silver,
優しい歌がいつまでも響きますように
may this gentle song echo forever.
悲しみもいつか去るのならいつまでもお返しを
If sadness will someday leave, I'll return it forever.
こんなに こんなに ささやかだ
How modest, how modest it is.
最後の 最後の 願いごと
Our final, final wish.
散り慣れた君だけが続けばよかった
It would have been fine if only you, used to scattering, could go on.
全てを護るだけの力があればよかった
It would have been fine if I had the power to protect everything.
乱れた夕日をずっと見ていたかった
I wanted to keep watching the disordered setting sun.
全てを護るだけの力があればよかった
It would have been fine if I had the power to protect everything.
散り慣れた君だけが続けばよかった
It would have been fine if only you, used to scattering, could go on,
全てを 捧げても
even if I sacrifice everything.
息を止めて そのままで 命を銀に浸かれ
Holding your breath, staying just like that, bathing your life in silver,
果てなき夢がいつまでも続きますように
may this endless dream continue forever.
消えたくないよ 消えたいで、ただそれだけを祈った
I don't want to disappear, I want to disappear—I prayed for just that alone.
最後の 最後の 幸せ
Our final, final happiness,
それでも それでも 触れるなら
still, still, if I can touch you—
許されない
I won't forgive you.
強く慣れる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I learned the reason why I could grow stronger; take me with you and let's move forward.
泥だらけの走馬燈に酔う
Intoxicated by the muddy revolving lantern.
こわばる心震える手は掴みたいものがある
My stiff heart and trembling hands have something they want to grasp—
それだけさ
that's all.
夜の匂いに空睨んでも
Even if I glare at the sky smelling of night,
変わっていけるのは自分自身だけ それだけさ
the only thing that can change is myself, and that's all.
強く慣れる理由を知った 僕を連れて進め
I learned the reason why I could grow stronger; take me with you and let's move forward.
どうしたって!
No matter what!
消せない夢も 止まれない今も
Unstoppable dreams, unstoppable present—
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can grow stronger for someone's sake,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
then thank you, my sadness.
強く慣れる理由を知った
I learned the reason why I could grow stronger;
僕を連れて進め
take me with you and let's move forward.
どうしたって
No matter what!
消せない夢も
Unstoppable dreams,
止まれない今も
unstoppable present—
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can grow stronger for someone's sake,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
then thank you, my sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
I learned why I lost when I was beaten down by the world.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ!
Bloom proudly, crimson lotus!
運命を照らして
Illumine our fate.
イナビカリの雑音が耳を刺す
The noise of lightning pierces my ears.
戸惑う心優しさだけじゃ守れないものがある?
Can tenderness alone not protect anything when I'm hesitating?
分かっているけど 水面下で絡まる善悪
I know that, but...
透けて見える偽善に天罰
Divine punishment on transparent hypocrisy.
(tell me why, tell me why...)
逸材の花より挑戦し続け咲いた一輪が美しい
A single flower that kept blooming through trials is more beautiful than any gem.
乱暴に敷き詰められたトゲだらけの道も
Even a path full of thorns roughly laid out
本気の僕だけに現れるから乗り越えてみせるよ
will only appear for my true self, so I'll overcome it.
簡単に片付けられた守れなかった夢も
Even dreams easily dismissed and left unprotected—
紅蓮的心臓に根を生やしこの血に宿っている
take root in this crimson heart and dwell in my blood.
人知れず儚い散りゆく結末 無情に破れた悲鳴の風吹く
A fleeting, unnoticed end that scatters away.
誰かの笑う影 誰かが泣き声
Someone's smiling shadow, someone's cry,
誰もが幸せを願っている どうしたって!
everyone is wishing for happiness, no matter what!
消せない夢も 止まれない今も
Unstoppable dreams, unstoppable present—
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can grow stronger for someone's sake,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
then thank you, my sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
I learned why I lost when I was beaten down by the world.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ! 運命を照らして
Bloom proudly, crimson lotus! Illumine our fate.
人知れず儚い散りゆく結末
A fleeting, unnoticed end that scatters away,
泥だらけの走馬燈に酔う
intoxicated by the muddy revolving lantern.
誰もが笑顔だけ 誰かの泣き声
Everyone just smiles, someone's crying voice—
誰もが幸せを願っている
everyone is wishing for happiness.
どうしたって消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what, unstoppable dreams and present—
誰かのために強くなれるなら
if I can grow stronger for someone,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
thank you, sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて負ける意味を知った
I learned why I lost when I was beaten down by the world.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ! 運命を照らして
Bloom proudly, crimson lotus! Illumine our fate.
運命を照らして
Illumine our fate.
やったぜー！やったぜー！
We did it! We did it!
ということで、ENからBaeが来てくれました！
And so, Bae from EN came to join us!
来ちゃいました！ハコス・ベールズです！せんぱーい！
I came! It's Hakos Baelz! Senpai!
はい！お誕生日おめでとーーー！
Yes! Happy birthdayyy!
ありが、ハッピ、ハッピー、まあくる、ハッピーバースデー！
Th- Thank you, happi, happy, ma-kuru, happy birthday!
ハッピバースデー！ハッピバースデー！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
いやあ、本当に呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Man, thank you so much for inviting me!
ありがとうね！あの、めっちゃめちゃ仲いいんだよね。
Thank you! You know, we're actually super, super close.
あの、本当仲良しで、あの、結構焼肉に行くんですよ。
Yeah, we're really close, and we actually go eat Yakiniku quite often.
もうルーティンになってますね、本当に。
It's totally become a routine for us, really.
きたスタに コンビニに寄って アイス買って
Stopping by a convenience store on the way to Kitasta,
アイス食べながら散歩して帰るみたいなの結構やってるんだけど
eating ice cream while taking a walk on the way home, I do that a lot.
そうです。
That's right.
結構やってるんだけど、そうです。
I do that a lot, that's right.
まこうね、なんか3次元ライブだけでコラボしてんの
Like this, collaborating only for 3D lives...
確かに！
True!
本当に、普段2人でなんかゲーム配信とかコラボしてないですよね。
Seriously, we don't usually collaborate on game streams or anything just the two of us, right?
いや、そうなのよ。あの、カバ動画とかで
No, that's right. Like, cover videos and stuff,
結構ずっとお互いのチャンネルでコラボして
we've collaborated on each other's channels for a long time,
そうだよね。
that's true.
一緒にデジウニ作を3次元で歌って、
Singing DejiUni's work together in 3D,
で、トワのグリーンここ歌って、でもゲーム配信は
and Towa sings Green here, but for game streams,
もっとゲームしよう？そうだよね。
let's play more games? That's right.
そうだよね、そうなんだよ。もっとゲームしよう。ゲーム。うん。
That's right, that's it. Let's play more games. Games. Yeah.
じゃあ、直近で...
Then, recently...
鼻水出た。
I got a runny nose.
やりたいと思います。
I'd like to do it.
やりたいと思います！
I'd like to do it!
はい！えーということで、
Yes! Um, with that said,
ま、グリーンはね、あのベイが歌がね上手でかっこよく歌えるので、
well, for Green, Baelz sings so well and coolly,
何言ってるんですか！
What are you talking about!
先輩は先輩の方がね、なんかそんなこんなにカッコいい、大好きな先輩と、
Senpai, Senpai is way cooler, my favorite Senpai,
なんかこんな、あのグリーン歌えてできて嬉しいです、とっても。
and I'm so happy to be able to sing Green like this, really.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんかちょっと恥ずかしいから次行くか。あ、あ。ね。
It's kind of embarrassing, so let's move on. Ah, ah. Right.
ね。てことで、次の曲へ...だまされた！
Right. With that said, to the next song... I was tricked!
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The blue season that seems to continue forever,
四つ並ぶ目の前を遮るものは何もない
there is nothing blocking the four eyes lined up in front.
アスファルト、蝉時雨を反射して
Reflecting the asphalt, the cicada's drizzle,
きみという沈黙が聞こえなくなる
the silence called you can no longer be heard.
この日々が色褪せる
These days are fading away,
僕と違うきみを知ってしまっても
even if I've come to know you, who are different from me.
置き忘れてきた永遠の底に
In the depths of eternity left behind,
今でも青が淀んでいる
blue still stagnates there,
今でも青は澄んでいる
blue is still clear there.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter what prayers or words,
近づけるのに、届かなかった
couldn't get closer, couldn't reach.
まるで、静かな恋のような
Like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏の色のなか
in the summer color that ran down my cheek,
きみを呪う言葉がずっと
the words cursing you are still
喉の奥につかえてる
stuck in the back of my throat.
「また会えるよね」って
"We'll meet again," —
声にならない声
a voice that could not become a voice.
無限に膨張する銀河の星の粒のように
Like the grains of stars in the infinitely expanding galaxy,
指の隙間を零れた
they spilled through the gaps between my fingers.
きみの笑顔も多くの憂いを
Your smile and your many sorrows,
見落とした孤独や闇尽くして
the loneliness and darkness I overlooked, exhausting them,
花束を抱いて咲いて散っていく きみにさよなら
holding a bouquet, blooming and scattering, goodbye to you.
今でも青が淀んでいる
Blue still stagnates there,
今でも青は澄んでいる
blue is still clear there.
どんな祈りも言葉も近づけるのに届かなかった
No matter what prayers or words, couldn't get closer, couldn't reach.
まるで静かな恋のような
Like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏の色のなか きみを呪う言葉がずっと
in the summer color that ran down my cheek, the words cursing you are still
喉の奥につかえてる
stuck in the back of my throat.
また会えるよねって 声にならない声
"We'll meet again," — a voice that could not become a voice,
無限に膨張する星の粒のように指の隙間
like the grains of stars in the infinitely expanding galaxy, the gap of fingers...
「青のすみか」でしたー！どうだった、みんな？
That was "Ao no Sumika"! How was it, everyone?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
かっこよかった？Thank you、ありがとう。
Was it cool? Thank you, thank you.
もうかっこいい曲だからね、すごい歌いたかったんで今日歌えてよかったです。ありがとう！
It's such a cool song, I really wanted to sing it, so I'm glad I got to sing it today. Thank you!
そして、なんとあと1曲歌います！まだ行かないでね、いい？
And, what's more, I'll sing one more song! Don't go yet, okay?
えーこちらラスト1曲は、えーなんと4月に募集したアレンジソングコンテストの曲になっております！いえーい！
Um, this last song is, um, from the arrange song contest we held in April! Yay!
えー覚えてる方いらっしゃいますでしょうか？（笑）
Um, does anyone remember it? (Haha)
今日ね、えー歌わせていただきたいと思います。えー募集したのが、「Purple Disease」と「Palette」っていうトワのオリジナルソングを募集したんですけれど、たくさんの応募がありました。ありがとうございます！
Today, um, I'd like to sing it. Um, I solicited for "Purple Disease" and "Palette," Towa's original songs, and we got a lot of entries. Thank you!
いえーい！
Yay!
いや今日ね、いやもう本当にめっちゃいい曲が何曲もあったんですよ。で、絞るのがすごいたくさん考えて考えて1曲、これだ！これだ！っていうのを決めて
Man, today, really, there were so many really good songs. And narrowing it down, I thought and thought and decided, this is it! This is it!
今日この配信で、えー1曲歌うのと
And today on this stream, um, singing one song and...
あとその、このあとのねメンバーシップ配信の、限定の配信でもう1曲歌うので、このあとのメンゲンのアンコールライブもぜひ皆さん見ててください！
and after that, in the membership stream, the limited stream, I'll sing another song, so please check out the encore live after the membership stream too!
はい！で、この配信で歌うのは、えーロイさんアレンジの「Purple Disease」を歌いたいと思います！
Yes! And for the song I'll sing on this stream, um, I'd like to sing "Purple Disease" arranged by Roy-san!
すごいかっこいい曲、元々すごいくかっこよかったんだけど、さらにスタイリッシュな感じのアレンジをしてくれているので、えーぜひ聞いていってくれたらなと思います。よろしくお願いします！
It's an amazing song, it was already super cool, but he made it even more stylish, so I hope you'll listen to it. Please look forward to it!
はい！ということで、はい、グッズの情報は一番最後にまとめてお送りするので、グッズ購入したいよって方は最後までよろしくお願いします！
Yes! So, yes, I'll send the goods information summarized at the very end, so if you want to buy goods, please stay until the end!
ということで、ラストの曲「Purple Disease」行きましょう！
With that, let's go with the last song, "Purple Disease"!
ohh ohh purple disease
Oh oh, purple disease,
ohh ohh 血液に
Oh oh, in my blood,
ohh ohh purple disease
Oh oh, purple disease,
ohh ohh 狂いやすい
Oh oh, driving me mad.
空腹なクランケ
A starving patient,
もう12時だっけ
Is it already 12?
餌付けしてやる
I'll feed you up.
臓器まで蝕む yeah
Gnawing down to your organs, yeah.
ウイルス性の偏愛
Viral infatuation,
吐息 舐め回い
Breaths and licks,
あでやかなのは
The only one who's dazzling
君 君だけだ
Is you, just you.
視線気にするほど暇じゃないのさ
I'm not idle enough to care about gazes.
獲物 人捻りする
Toying with my prey, a single twist.
苦い色の刺激 誘引
Bitter-hued stimuli, allured.
忍び寄る 紫に怖えて
Creeping in, trembling in purple.
いいよ 私を選んで
It's alright, choose me.
いいよ 幸せに後悔してよ
It's alright, regret it happily.
墜ちてよ この
Fall into this...
regret regret regret
紫の魔術 禁断の果実
Purple magic, forbidden fruit.
逃げるな おこちゃまだな
Don't run away, you're just a kid.
eat ya 一口で感染
Eat ya, infected in one bite.
eat ya 甘くて苦いチョコレート
Eat ya, sweet yet bitter chocolate.
知らないの
You don't know?
i'm 危険 危険 危険
I'm danger, danger, danger.
無防備に近寄ってよ ほら
Come close defencelessly, hey.
未熟な威嚇 構えて your love
Immature threats bracing your love.
why why why ってさ
Asking why, why, why?
溺れたいんでしょ
You want to drown in it, right?
愛 愛 愛って 気の病
Love, love, love is a mental illness.
purple disease
ohh ohh purple disease
Oh oh, purple disease.
その身も心も 子鹿のいいこ
Body and soul like a helpless fawn.
あやされたまま 毒に侵されていいの
It's fine to be coddled and consumed by poison.
破滅ってハッピーエンド
Ruination is a happy ending.
シアワセって結構面倒
Happiness is quite a hassle.
任せて身を得 致死性の仮病
Leave it to me, a fatal feigned illness.
劣等感ってやつ? 被支配欲ですか
Inferiority complex? Or a desire to be controlled?
君のこと分かってる
I know all about you,
dnaのレベル yeah
Down to your DNA, yeah.
さあ印づけたり 引きずり降ろし
Now marking you, dragging you down.
紫煙見えた 火が 火が上がるんだ
Purple smoke in sight, a fire, a fire rises.
何も知らないんだね 君は
"You don't know a thing, do you?"
って言われたみたいに見えるんだ
You look like you want to be told that.
甘い声の蛇の viruses
Viruses of a snake with a sweet voice.
隠したまま近づくんだよ
Drawing closer while keeping it hidden.
いいよ 私を選んで
It's alright, choose me.
いいよ 幸せに後悔してよ
It's alright, regret it happily.
墜ちてよ この
Fall into this...
regret regret
いいよ 心の奥を
It's alright, into the depths of your heart.
いいよ 音もなく蝕んでいこうよ
It's alright, let me gnaw on it silently.
高鳴る この
Surging up, this...
regret regret regret
紫の捕食 太陽の補色
Purple predation, complementary to the sun.
絡んだ 罠なんだ
Intertwined, a trap.
eat ya 身体の中
Eat ya, inside your body.
eat ya 侵入して 燃やす fire
Eat ya, invading and burning fire.
もう良いや
Enough already.
you're 犠牲 犠牲 犠牲
You're a sacrifice, sacrifice, sacrifice.
軽率に手伸ばしてよ ほら
Reach out your hand carelessly, hey.
免疫の薄い 所 your love
Your love with weak immunity.
why why why って
Asking why, why, why?
止まらないでしょ
You can't stop, can you?
愛 愛 愛って 終わりがない
Love, love, love has no end.
why why why って
Asking why, why, why?
嚥まれないんでしょ
You won't be swallowed up, will you?
愛 愛 愛って 気の病
Love, love, love is a mental illness.
purple disease
ohh ohh purple disease
Oh oh, purple disease.
ohh ohh 血液に
Oh oh, in my blood.
ohh ohh purple disease
Oh oh, purple disease.
ohh ohh
Oh oh...
purple disease
ohh ohh purple disease
ohh ohh 血液に
Ohh ohh, in my blood
ohh ohh purple disease
ohh ohh 狂おしい
Ohh ohh, so maddening
空腹なクランケ もう12時だっけ
A hungry patient, is it already 12?
餌付けしてやる 臓器まで蝕む yeah
I'll feed you, consuming even your organs, yeah
ウイルス性の偏愛 吐息 舐め合い
Viral obsession, sighs, licking wounds
逢い引きでいいのは君君だけだ
The only one I want to meet in secret is you
視線気にするほど暇じゃないの
I don't have time to care about others' gazes
獲物 人攫いする
Prey, abducting people
苦い色の刺激 誘引 忍び寄る 紫に怯えて
Bitter stimulation, creeping up, fear the purple
いいよ 私を選んで
It's fine, choose me
いいよ 幸せに後悔してよ
It's fine, regret your happiness
堕ちてよこの regret regret regret
Fall into this regret, regret, regret
紫の魔術 禁断の果実
Purple magic, forbidden fruit
huh 逃げるな おちゅうちまだな
Huh, don't run away, you're not ready yet
eat ya 一口で感染
Eat ya, infected in a single bite
eat ya 甘くて苦いチョコレート
Eat ya, sweet and bitter chocolate
知らないの i'm 危険 危険 危険
Didn't you know? I'm dangerous, dangerous
無防備に近寄ってよほら 未熟な威嚇構えて your love
Approach defenselessly, holding up threats for love
why why why って呑まれたいんでしょう
You want to be swallowed, saying "why, why, why"?
愛 愛 愛 って気の病 purple disease
Love is a mental illness, purple disease
ohh ohh purple disease
その身も心も子鹿のいいこ
Both body and mind, a good little fawn
匿されたまま毒に侵されていいの
Is it okay to be tainted by hidden poison?
破滅ってハッピーエンド
Ruination is a happy ending
シアワセって結構面倒
And happiness is quite troublesome
と言うことで、本日は常闇トワ生誕祭2024を見にきてくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching Tokoyami Towa's Birthday 2024!
いかがだったでしょうか？
How was it?
たくさん感想やスクリーンショットをSNSなどに投稿していただけると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you post your thoughts and screenshots!
そして、グッズのお知らせです！イエーイ！
And now, an announcement about merchandise! Yay!
今回のグッズのイラストは、るるどママに描いていただきました！じゃーん！
The illustrations for this merch were drawn by rurudo-mama! Ta-da!
夏なので、えー、水着にして、えー、見ちゃいました！
Since it's summer, I made it swimwear and took a look!
はい、全部で4種類となっております。
Right, there are 4 types in total.
え、ホログラムアクリルパネル、トワ様と春夏秋冬ランダム缶バッジ、
Hologram acrylic panel, four-seasons random can badge,
ぬいぐるみ ブレイクver.以上、眷属クリアショルダーバッグ
plushie Break ver., and kenzoku clear shoulder bag,
の4点となっておりまして、え、単品購入もできますし、フルセットの購入もできます！
making 4 items. You can buy them individually or as a full set!
フルセットの場合、複製サインか数量限定で直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきまーす！
The full set comes with a replica or hand-signed bromide!
はい、そしてグッズの詳細です！まず1点目、ドン！
Right, and now for the merch details! First item, boom!
え、るるどママ書き下ろしホログラムアクリルパネル！
rurudo-mama's newly drawn hologram acrylic panel!
え、キラキラのね、ホログラム仕様の水着トワ様をぜひ飾ってみてください！
Please display this sparkly hologram-spec swimwear Towa-sama!
めっちゃね、可愛く描いてもらったし、このね、何と言っても後ろのビビの表情とか、それがね、ビビのもっちり具合がすごい可愛いすぎるのよ！
She drew me so cute, and BiBi's chubbiness is just too cute!
なので、ぜひチェックをお願いします！
So please definitely check it out!
そして2つ目、ドン！
And second, boom!
トワ様と春夏秋冬ランダム缶バッジ！
Towa-sama and four-seasons random can badge!
こちらはね、しろ先生に書き下ろししていただいた春夏秋冬の、え、可愛いミニキャラ缶バッジとなっております。
Cute mini-character can badges of the four seasons by Shiro-sensei.
1つ1つね、服も違うデザインで、あのしろ先生が書き下ろししてくださって、可愛くしてくれてるので、ぜひチェックしてどんな感じの服なのかなとかを実物を見てみてほしいなと思います！
Check them out and see what the clothes look like in person!
え、男の子も女の子もぜひゲットしてほしいし、推しバックを作ってほしいなと思ってまーす！
I hope both boys and girls will get them and make an oshi bag!
はい、そして3つ目、ドン！
Right, and third, boom!
ブレイクver.のぬいぐるみ！ウィー！
Break ver. plushie! Wee!
なんと、えー、この後にも紹介するショルダーバッグに入るサイズのぬいぐるみが生誕ライブ衣装のトワ様のぬいぐるみとなっております！
A plushie in her birthday live outfit, sized for the shoulder bag!
え、こちら、細かいところもね、再現してくれているので、ぜひお手に取ってチェックしてみてください！
It faithfully recreates even the fine details, so check it out!
はい、そして最後4つ目！
Right, and finally the fourth one!
ドン！眷属クリアショルダーバッグ！
Boom! Kenzoku clear shoulder bag!
ハー、フーフー！
Haah, foofoo!
え、こちらは先ほど紹介した生誕ライブ衣装のトワ様のぬいぐるみが入る仕様となってまして、え、もちろんホロライブフレンズもしっかり入る大きさのバッグとなっております！
Fits the birthday plushie and Hololive Friends too!
え、男性でも女性でも使いやすいデザイン、カラーとなっておりますので、ぜひ普段使いもしてください！
An easy design and color for daily wear!
おい、そしてこちらが、え、フルセット特定のチェキ風ブロマイドカードです！
And this is the full-set exclusive Polaroid-style bromide card!
フルセットにはちょっと数量限定にはなりますが、直筆サインがついてくるので、ぜひこの後の概要欄のサイトからチェックして購入してみてください！
The full set comes with a hand-signed card, so check the site!
ということで以上グッズのご告知でした！ありがとー！サンキュー！
And that's all for the merch announcement! Thank you!
今日は本当に見に来てくれてありがとうございます！この後はメンバー限定でライブもするので、お楽しみに！まったねー！
Thank you for watching! I'll do a member-only live stream!
常闇トワ生誕祭2024 COLORFUL
[Tokoyami Towa Birthday Festival 2024: COLORFUL]